In this video, we're going to be using Task Manager in source monitor,
totally troubleshooting Windows Server device.
So, if you have an issue with Windows Server,
for example, you have application that is not totally responding anymore,
we can use Task Manager to actually stop that application or close the application to tally.
So, let's say I have Internet Explorer at the moment on this Windows Server,
and if I go to Task Manager, here you can see that we can see that the apps that are running right now
is the Internet Explorer resource and performance monitor.
We have our server manager and we have our task manager.
I can see some of the background processes which are also running on this device.
And if I go to Performance, here you can see we have performance of this device.
You can see this CPU, you would have the central processing unit.
And let me just show you once, if, for example, I close Internet Explorer,
you can see that my CPU actually rises and then it will drop again.
So, let's try to open Internet Explorer.
So, here we go. You can see when I open Internet Explorer,
look at what happens to my CPU, it rises and then it drops.
Sometimes you can go to your CPU and see if, for example, your device becomes very,
very slow and normal responsive, you can go to your CPU from the Task Manager
and actually see what is utilization, the speed and also you can see the process.
And, for example, so we can also click on Memory and here we can see how many more it's been used
at this moment. You can see in use, it's about 1.9 gigabyte.
I'm committed, you can see it's about 2.8 gigabyte.
And, the page pool is about 1991.9 MB, and the non-page pool is about 109 mega bytes.
So, actually, you can see, but if you're using Windows Server, definitely,
you want to measure that you have more memory or category of Windows Server,
because sometimes, you know, you're a Windows Server, you install it with your domain
controller, install multiple applications or multiple programs on that domain controller.
Or, different users are actually connecting to that domain controller using the remote desktop management tool.
So, you want to measure that you have enough memory, at this moment, because of this training purpose,
I only have about 2 gigabytes that is actually being used on this Windows Server domain controller.
And, here on our users, you can see how many users or which users are actually logged on to this device.
So, if, for example, you have multiple users, you use that as well as testing the Windows Server is a remote desktop management tool.
Definitely, you're going to see a list of users here, and how many users have logged on to your device.
And, we can also go to details, and see all the different applications that are running and rising.
It process ID, and also, you can see how many CPU apps have been used.
And, here, you can see our services, we can actually, we have the option actually, for example, we can actually start a service or stop a service that have been started from a task manager.
You can actually manage the service, go back into your start menu, and then open the service, perform the task manager.
We can also manage the service.
So, and, also, you can see we have the open resource monitor.
So, here, you can see we have our resource monitor.
Our resource monitor gives off full details information of our CPU usage.
For example, if I go to my CPU, you can see that we have some of the programs that are actually being running behind the scene.
Let me try to expand this down.
Here, you can see all the different program that are running and the thread, and also, you can see the CPU that's being used by this program.
So, you can see, for example, we have a performance monitor, which is actually using about 11% of our CPU.
And, also, you can see the task monitor is using about 2%.
So, you can have an ideal of how many CPU is being used by each of your program that is running behind the scene.
And, also, we can also go to memory from here.
From the memory, we can also see which of the apps is consuming much memory.
For example, you can see in use, you can see that the color is actually green.
You can see the modifier is done by, and we have about three, three, this is actually changing.
And, also, if I go to disk, here, you can see the apps or program that are actually consuming more disk on your device.
And, here, you can see we have a lot of programs, but you can see small programs that are running behind the scene,
which are consuming at how many bytes these programs are actually consuming.
And, if I go to the network here, also, the same, we can actually see which programs that are only using our network,
a data to other moment.
And, also, you can see this is sent by it and received by it by seconds.
So, this is how you can actually use the search monitor, your task monitor to actually monitor your device and try to actually find out which problem at all or which of the application is making your device to actually run very, very slow.